University of Connecticut
© 2004 University of Connecticut
University of Connecticut, Alumni Association Records.
undated, 1881-1986.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
University of Connecticut. Alumni Association.
4.8 linear feet.
MSS19980253
The collection contains early records of the Alumni Association associated with the University.
History
On 15 June 1888 ,a meeting was held at the Storrs Agricultural School to form an Alumni Association. Isacc B. Wakeman ’85 was elected as the first president. A list of graduates was read at the first meeting, including six from each of the Classes of 1882, 1884, and 1885 and twenty-nine from 1886, 1887, and 1888 for a total of forty-seven alumni. Dues for the new association were set at $1.
The Association first became interested in supporting students in 1890 as it set up a $10 prize for a member of the graduating class who passed a practical examination before an alumni committee. The Association also appointed a committee to encourage the appointment of an alumnus on the Board of Trustees. The Constitution and By-laws of 1888 were put into print in 1892. Dr. Andrew L. Hyde was appointed the first Alumni Trustee in 1895.
On 15 June 1894, it was voted to change the Association's name to the Alumni Association of the Storrs Agricultural School and College. In 1895, the name was once again changed to the Alumni Association of Storrs Agricultural College.
In 1921 it was voted to have an Alumni Secretary; the position to be funded jointly by the Association and the University. Mr. A.J. Brundage, Class of 1910, was engaged as the first Secretary on a part-time basis. The next Field Secretary was Robert H. Mathewson (1922-1924) who developed an alumni newspaper, The Connecticut Alumnus.
During the early twenties, the By Laws were re-written, and the dues increased to $2 annually or $34 for life membership. In 1933, the Association became the Connecticut State College Alumni Association, and during 1939 the University of Connecticut Alumni Association. Willard Eddy was president of the Alumni Association when the Board of Directors selected George E. Pinckney as Alumni Field Secretary. Mr. Pinckney served twenty-four years as Alumni Secretary.
The Constitution and By Laws were revised in 1961 and dues were increased to $5. The alumni body numbered 24,000 in 1962 when George Pinckney retired and Reuben B. Johnson became the first director of alumni relations. In November 1962, President Babbidge and Reuben Johnson developed a new role for alumni in the establishment of a "Margin for Excellence" program that successfully continues today.
The mission of the Alumni Association is to strengthen lifelong bonds between all members of the UConn family by inspiring pride and providing quality programs and services which enhance the diverse university community.
Additional information about the Association, its activities and officers is available at the Alumni Association homepage.
Scope and Content
The collection contains administrative and financial records of the earlier years of the organization, in addition to reports, correspondence, publications and similar documentation of the activities of the organization and the alumni of the institution. As appropriate, materials collected from Alumni have been added to the collection.
Arrangement
Series I: Administrative Records ( undated, 1881-1945, 1961, 1970 ) includes correspondence, reports, financial and administrative records documenting the activities of the Association.
Series II: Alumni Record Cards ( 1883-1942 ) contains information cards on alumni of the institution.
Series III: Alumni Correspondence ( undated, 1961-1966 ) contains correspondence, notes and clippings from Alumni.
Series IV: Class Materials ( undated, 1924-1986 ) contains correspondence, financial records and materials pertaining to reunions for specific classes.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of material pertaining to the University's history. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Commencement Clarion Dodd Periodicals
C.A.C. Four Songs Dodd Call No.
Directory: Faculty, Staff and Students Dodd Periodicals
Official Weekly Bulletin, Division of Student Personnel. Dodd Periodicals
News Bulletin Dodd Periodicals
Two audio tapes and 6 slide carousels [Multimedia] associated with presentations, 2 buttons and several paper hats [Memorabilia] have been placed in the indicated University Archives collections.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut Alumni Association.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Photocopies.; Notes.; Resolutions.; Sound recordings.; Poems.; Bylaws.; Newsletters.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials were transferred to Archives & Special Collections at an undetermined date prior to 1995.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Administrative Records, undated, 1881-1945, 1961, 1970
  - Activities, 1930-1934 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Board, C.A.C. Alumni Association, 1924-1927 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Councils, undated, 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Employment and related matters, undated (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Alumni List, 1881-1919 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Lists, 1898-1944 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Trustee, 1929, 1931 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Announcements, 1925-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Athletic Loans, undated, 1931, 1933 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Beach (President Charles) Portrait Fund, undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees, 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees--Resolution (Gag Rule), 1935 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Budget, 1933-1934 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Budget Campaign, undated, 1923-1931 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Budget Campaign, 1924-1930 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Budget Campaign--Appeal Letter, 1932 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - C.S.C. Mascot, undated, 1934-1936 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Change of Name, 1932-1933 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Chapter (Locals)
    - Boston area, 1934-1937 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - Bridgeport, 1935-1936 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Bristol/New Britain, 1935-1936 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Eastern Massachusetts/Northern Connecticut, 1925, 1931-1932 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - Fairfield County, 1934-1936 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - Hartford, 1932-1935 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - Hartford/Hartford County (Co-ed), 1932-1936 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - Litchfield, undated (Box 1:, Folder 26)
    - Middletown, 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
    - New Haven, 1932-1937 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
    - New Haven, 1939-1946 (Box 6:, Folder 113)
    - New Haven, 1944-1945 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
    - New Jersey, 1931-1936 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
    - New York, 1931-1937 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
    - Norwich/New London, 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
    - Others, 1936 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
    - Philadelphia, 1931-1936 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
    - Stamford, 1935-1937 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
    - Waterbury, 1932-1934 (Box 1:, Folder 36)
    - Windham County, undated (Box 1:, Folder 37)
    - Worcester, MA area, undated (Box 1:, Folder 38)
  - Chapter Assignments, undated, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 39)
  - Clock Pledges, 1927 (Box 1:, Folder 40)
  - College colors, 1928-1929 (Box 1:, Folder 41)
  - Constitution and By-Laws for Alumni Local Cloubs (Chapters), undated (Box 1:, Folder 42)
  - Constitution and By-Laws of the Alumni Association of C.A.C., 1924 (Box 1:, Folder 43)
  - Contributions, 1931-1932 (Box 1:, Folder 44)
  - Contributions, 1932-1933 (Box 1:, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence
    - A, 1944-1945 (Box 1:, Folder 46)
    - B, 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 47)
    - B, 1944-1945 (Box 1:, Folder 48)
    - C, 1931-1934 (Box 1:, Folder 49)
    - D - E, 1944-1945 (Box 1:, Folder 50)
    - Employment Letters, 1932 (Box 1:, Folder 51)
    - Employment Letters, 1933 June - October (Box 1:, Folder 52)
    - Employment Letters, 1933 (Box 1:, Folder 53)
    - Employment Letters, 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 54)
    - F - H, 1944-1945 (Box 1:, Folder 55)
    - Fairfield State Hospital, 1933 (Box 1:, Folder 56)
    - I - K, 1943-1945 (Box 1:, Folder 57)
    - Jorgensen, A.N., 1940-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 58)
    - L - N, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 59)
    - Neuro Psychiartric Institute, 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 60)
    - P - R, 1943-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 61)
    - Placement Office, 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 62)
    - Recruitment, 1940 (Box 6:, Folder 114)
    - S, undated, 1923-1931 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
    - S, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 64)
    - T, undated, 1925-1931 (Box 2:, Folder 65)
    - T, 1934-1938 (Box 2:, Folder 66)
    - T, 1945 (Box 2:, Folder 67)
    - Teacher placement, 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 68)
    - U - V, undated, 1925-1931 (Box 2:, Folder 69)
    - U - V/Unknown addresses, 1932, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 70)
    - W, undated, 1924-1931 (Box 2:, Folder 71)
    - W, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 72)
    - White House, 1947-1948, 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 73)
    - X - Z, undated, 1921-1931 (Box 2:, Folder 74)
  - Defense of the College, undated, 1926, 1929 (Box 2:, Folder 75)
  - Election of Alumni Representative to the Board of Trustees, 1961 (Box 6:, Folder 110)
  - Ex-Members of the Classes, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 76)
  - Executive Board, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 77)
  - Expenses, 1931-1932 (Box 2:, Folder 78)
  - Expenses, 1932-1933 (Box 2:, Folder 79)
  - Expenses, 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 80)
  - Finances, 1932 (Box 2:, Folder 81)
  - Help the College Pilgrimage Committee, 1920 (Box 6:, Folder 112)
  - Homecoming, 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 82)
  - Homecoming, 1935 (Box 2:, Folder 83)
  - Homecoming, 1936 (Box 2:, Folder 84)
  - Lamson (George H.) Memorial, 1932-1933 (Box 2:, Folder 85)
  - "Last Appeal" Responses A - I (sent May 1937) (Box 2:, Folder 86)
  - "Last Appeal" Responses J - Z, 1937 (Box 2:, Folder 87)
  - Legislative material, 1945 (Box 2:, Folder 88)
  - Minutes, undated, 1901 (Box 2:, Folder 89)
  - Minutes, 1921-1922 (Box 2:, Folder 90)
  - Minutes, 1925-1927 (Box 2:, Folder 91)
  - Minutes, 1928-1931 (Box 2:, Folder 92)
  - Newspaper Contest, 1922 (Box 2:, Folder 93)
  - Outgoing letters and materials, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 94)
  - Parking, 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 95)
  - Pharmacy, College of, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 96)
  - Poetry, undated, 1945 (Box 2:, Folder 97)
  - Projects, undated, 1924, 1928-1929 (Box 2:, Folder 98)
  - R.O.T.C., undated (Box 2:, Folder 99)
  - Reorganization of Athletic Department, ca. 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 100)
  - Requisitions, 1945 (Box 2:, Folder 101)
  - Reunion, 1922-1924 (Box 2:, Folder 102)
  - Reunion, 1934 (Box 2:, Folder 103)
  - Rhode Island game and Football banquet, 1922 (Box 2:, Folder 104)
  - Servicemen forms, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 105)
  - State Legislature, 1933 (Box 2:, Folder 106)
  - Student Union building campaign, 1939, 1944-1945 (Box 2:, Folder 107)
  - Varsity Club, 1944 (Box 2:, Folder 108)
  - Wattles, Willard, undated (Box 2:, Folder 109)
- Series II: Alumni Record Cards, 1883-1942
  - 1883-1919 (Box 3)
  - 1920-1932 (Box 4)
  - 1933-1942 (Box 5)
- Series III: Alumni Correspondence, undated, 1961-1966
  - Forman, Camille, undated, 1961-1966 (Box 6:, Folder 111)
- Series IV: Class Materials, undated, 1934-1986
  - Class of 1928
    - Correspondence and Roster, undated, 1968 (Box 7:, Folder 119)
  - Class of 1929
    - Correspondence, 1969-1984 (Box 7:, Folder 115)
    - Financial Records, 1934-1978 (Box 7:, Folder 116)
    - Reunions, 1934-1986 (Box 7:, Folder 117)
    - Rosters, undated (Box 7:, Folder 118)